talesofarantingginger.com 2017-11-20

# Privacy, disclosure & Giveaway Policy - Tales of a Ranting Ginger

Thank you for entering a giveaway on **Tales of a Ranting Ginger**. Giveaways are a great way for companies to help promote a product or campaign. All opinions expressed are honest and of my own. Any information taken from a second source is quoted or referenced. As a Canadian mom blogger I try my best to always keep my readers I mind when accepting giveaways. So most often they are open to Canada 

**Rules** – Giveaways hosted here are most always open to Canada. Whenever possible they are open to both Canada and USA. If the brands requests, Quebec will be excluded due to laws for that province on prizes over $100

All mandatory entries **MUST** be completed correctly before additional entries are counted. If you do not complete the mandatory entry your additional entries will be deleted.

If you are not eligible for the giveaway (see rules within post) your entries will not be counted. 

All entries are always verified. 

Please leave your Twitter ID and Facebook name (first and last initial) for these kinds of entries. 

Tweet entries MUST include the URL to your tweet (right click on time stamp in tweet to get this). 

Newsletter subscriptions must be verified in your inbox to count. If your twitter account is private I can not verify and will request a follow to see your tweets. 

**_Winners MUST confirm their win notification within 48 hours of the winners email being sent. If you do not respond, a new winner will be  selected._**

**IP addresses**. If it is assumed the same person has entered using multiple emails or changed names for multiple entries, your entries will be deleted and not counted. We understand that schools, families and work places have multiple people entering. This decision will be at the discretion of the blog owner.

**Entrants-** 1 email per entrant, if multiple emails are being used for the same person you may be disqualified  
  
**Policies-** Tales of a Ranting Ginger is **NOT** responsible for shipping. If your prize does not arrive in a timely manner (6-8 weeks) please send me an email (Gingermommyrants at gmail dot com) and I will do my best to track it down and contact the sponsor. Please do not email me looking for your prize before 6 weeks time.  Do not contact the sponsor directly as often the company who runs their websites, social media etc is not the same as who the blogger is dealing with in most cases. 

Tales of a Ranting Ginger has the right to ban or disqualify anyone who is not eligible to win a prize or has broken the rules in any way 

**Rafflecopter** – While using Rafflecopter to promote giveaways, I will be using their pick a winner feature. **If you sign into Rafflecopter with your Facebook account** , make sure the email linked to it is one you check often as this is were your winner notification will go.  
  
**Giveaway tools** – When I use GT for a giveaway, all entries will be verified and the pick a winner feature will determine the winner(s) NOTE The names on these widgets do not always match up to the names commenting on the blog. This is why we ask for the name you used when commenting. 

**Disclosure** -Tales of a Ranting Ginger is happy to have _won_ the opportunity to review these great products. All opinions expressed are honest and of my own. NOT influenced in any way. 

**Sponsored content** – Some posts, ads and links are sponsored on this blog. All opinions are my own and honest. Often product is received in exchange for my review and promotion or giveaways.

“Our website may contain affiliate marketing links, which means we may get paid commission on sales of those products or services we write about. Our editorial content is not influenced by advertisers or affiliate partnerships. This disclosure is provided in accordance with the [Federal Trade Commission’s 16 CFR § 255.5: Guides Concerning the Use of Endorsements and Testimonials in Advertising](http://www.ftc.gov/sites/default/files/attachments/press-releases/ftc-publishes-final-guides-governing-endorsements-testimonials/091005revisedendorsementguides.pdf).”

**Privacy policy**

This privacy policy sets out how Tales of a Ranting Ginger  uses and protects any information that you give while using www.talesofarantingginger.com

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Tales of a Ranting Ginger   may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from April 02/15.

**What we collect**

We may collect the following information:

  * contact information including email address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

**What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails if you opted into receiving the newsletter.

**Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. At no time will your information be sold or shared.

Information is only shared for giveaway fulfillment purposes.

**Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Advertising**

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is [http://www.gourmetads.com](http://www.gourmetads.com/). These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

**More about cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

**Opt out of cookies**

Gourmet Ads primary ad server is Appnexus and you can opt out of cookies from them by visiting ;  
<http://appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices> and Opting Out.

You can also opt out of cookies using the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page at this page;  
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>
